<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC
   "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" []>
<refentry id='gif2raw.1'>
<refentryinfo><date>2 May 2012</date></refentryinfo>
<refmeta>
<refentrytitle>gif2raw</refentrytitle>
<manvolnum>1</manvolnum>
<refmiscinfo class="source">GIFLIB</refmiscinfo>
<refmiscinfo class="manual">GIFLIB Documentation</refmiscinfo>
</refmeta>
<refnamediv id='name'>
<refname>gif2raw</refname>
<refpurpose>convert raw pixel data to a GIF</refpurpose>
</refnamediv>

<refsynopsisdiv id='synopsis'>

<cmdsynopsis>
  <command>gif2raw</command>
      <arg choice='opt'>-v</arg>
      <arg choice='plain'>-s 
      		<replaceable>width</replaceable>
      		<replaceable>height</replaceable></arg>
      <arg choice='opt'>-t</arg>
      <arg choice='opt'>-p <replaceable>color-map</replaceable></arg>
      <arg choice='opt'>-h</arg>
      <arg choice='opt'><replaceable>raw-file</replaceable></arg>
</cmdsynopsis>
</refsynopsisdiv>

<refsect1><title>Description</title>

<para>A program to dump raw pixels from GIFS or convert raw image data
into GIF files.  Only one image can be handled.  The default conversion
is GIF-to-raw; the -s option inverts this.</para>

<para>A raw image file is assumed to hold one pixel color in one byte,
and therefore the size of a raw file on input must be Width times
Height as specified by the -s option below.</para>

<para>If no input file is given, gif2raw will try to read a GIF or raw
data data from stdin.  The generated GIF or raw data is dumped to
stdout.</para>

</refsect1>
<refsect1><title>Options</title>

<variablelist>
<varlistentry>
<term>-v</term>
<listitem>
<para>Verbose mode (show progress).
Enables printout of running scan lines.</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>-s width height</term>
<listitem>
<para>Enables raw-to-GIF conversion. The dimensions of the image
<emphasis>must</emphasis> be specified in the command line.  The raw
image file size must be exactly width times weight bytes (each byte is
one pixel color).</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>-t</term>
<listitem>
<para>Textify. In GIF-to-raw mode, add 32 to the raw value of each pixel
emitted and emit \n at the end of each raster line. This maps raw pixel values
to printable ASCII chacters, but unhappy results will follow if any pixel
has a value greater than 95.</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-p ColorMapFile</term>
<listitem>
<para>Valid in raw-to-GIF mode only, Color map to load for given RAW
image.  This file has 4 integers in line (ColorIndex Red Green Blue),
and the ColorIndex is in order starting from 1. See gifclrmap, which
can also use/create these bitmap files. If no color map is specified,
uses the EGA 16 color palette as default color map.</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>-h</term>
<listitem>
<para>Print one line of command line help, similar to Usage above.</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
</variablelist>

</refsect1>
<refsect1><title>Author</title>

<para>Gershon Elber.</para>

</refsect1>
</refentry>
